你嗑药了, 当差的?
You high,popo?
有幽默感的警察,你查他的警车
cop with a sense of humor.You can check the cop car.
还有他的私人用车, 工作地点, 家里
Also check his personal car,work,home.
Foreman, 出去!
Foreman,get out!
只有我觉得好笑么?
Am I the only one who finds this funny?
你偷了我的论文
You stole my article.
我没偷
I wouldn't do that.
我们不是朋友 是同事
We're not friends,we're colleagues.
狗娘养的!
Ow! Son of a bitch!
现在你我都感染了
Now we're both exposed.
我会死的
I'm gonna die.
你死, 我死, 这些都不会发生
You die,I die.It's not gonna happen.
死亡时间, 12:26 P.M.
Time of death,12:26 P.M.
我要一把骨锯
I need a bone saw.
- 对不起, 爱莫能助,- 你说可以的
I'm sorry. I wish I could. --You said you
我只需要取很小一块他的大脑,如此而已
I just want a little tiny slice of this guy's brain,that's all I need.
找出即将杀死Foreman的东西
Just enough to tell me what's killing foreman.
一小片Joe的大脑也会造成公众恐慌
A thin slice of joe's brain could also cause a public health crisis.
没有必要每次都小题大做
It's not a good idea to scream "fire"every time somebody lights a match.
别轻描淡写的, House
Don't downplay this,house.
你把他们隔离肯定有原因
You put both of them in isolation for a reason.
Joe的死亡使生物安全等级上升为3
Joe's death elevates this situation to a biosafety level three.
噢, 3级
Ooh,level three.
应该找jack bauer,(24 男主角)
You should call jack bauer.
我找了疾病控制中心(CDC)
I called the cdc.
告诉他们我们会万分当心
Well,tell them i'll be really,really careful.
没有配套设备,不可能做到"万分当心"
We don't have the proper equipment for you to be really,really careful.
你想把Foreman怎么样都无所谓,但解剖必须由CDC进行
You can do whatever you want to foreman,but the cdc will do this autopsy.
随便, 问题是,3天之内能拿到结果都算快的了
Whatever.The point is,we'll be lucky to get results in three days.
我告诉他们这个是紧急事件
I told them how urgent this is.
他们怎么说?
And they told you?
3天后能拿到结果
We'll have the results in three days.
可惜
Aw,that's a shame.
Foreman看不到结果了,他将在36小时内死去
Because foreman will never get to know what it was.He'll be dead in 36 hours.
也许是中毒, 根本没传染性
Maybe this is a toxin.Maybe it's not contagious at all,
Foreman却要死在这个"也许"上
and you're killing foreman because of a maybe.
给你36小时, 你去查出来
Well,you have 36 hours to figure out which one it is.
Foreman过来, 快点
Foreman.Come here,fast.
怎么了?
What's going on?
他们什么时候来验尸?
When are they doing the autopsy?
你自己来, 马上
You're doing it.Now.
知道以前是怎么用冰锥做脑叶手术吗?
You ever study how they used to do ice pick lobotomies?
在医学院读到过, 为什么要我--
I read about it in med school.Why would I--
把冰锥顶在他的眼袋, 泪管的正上方
shove an ice pick into the eye socket.Just above the tear duct.
用榔头敲几下, 取出样本
Bang it a couple of times with a hammer,get a sample.
怎么回事?
What's going on,man?
Foreman, 不要做
Foreman,you can't do it.
那样你会违反--
You'll be in violation of--
- 没命了还用坐牢么,- 你
can't do the time if you're not alive.--You.
我要你换上防护服
I need you to suit up.
从Foreman医生那里拿回工具
Get that equipment away from dr. Foreman.
慢慢来, 伙计
take your time,guys.
你干吗不说些小心之类的?,那样不会错
Why don't you just tell him to go slow?Won't be your fault.
Foreman.
我们还不知道这是什么类型的感染
We don't even know what kind of contagion we're dealing with.
所以我们要凿开那人的脑袋
Which is why we need to chop into the guy's head.
- 这样很危险,- 对你来说没什么, foreman
It's dangerous.--Not to you,foreman.
还有其它方法来诊断
There are other ways to diagnose you.
是吗? 你知道?
Yeah?You have the answer?
Foreman, 动手
Foreman,do it now.
我警告你, 不要--
I am warning you,do not--
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我感觉不好
That didn't feel right.
他失明了
He's blind.
他以为自己能看见,跟那警察一样
He thinks he can see.Same as the cop.
给我个袋子盛样本
I need something to bag the sample.
算了吧, 你刚刚取了床垫的样本
Forget it.You just biopsied a mattress.
不不, 我没事
No,no,no.I'm fine.
House, 样品拿去, 去检查
House,there's the sample.Get it,test it.
快点去检查样品!
You gotta test that sample!
36小时的估计过于乐观了
Apparently I was optimistic about the 36 hours.
接下来将是无法遏止, 无法忍受的疼痛
Intractable,unbearable pain is up next.
关于验尸的事, 要不要再考虑下?
Sure you don't want to reconsider that whole autopsy thing?
眼睛是好的
physically,his eyes are fine.
问题在于和大脑隔离了
Problem's isolated to his brain.
枕叶的损伤从主要视皮层--
Damage to the occipital lobe extends from the primary visual cortex--
要不要检查细菌性脑膜炎?
should we test him for bacterial meningitis?
如果是脑膜炎, 他早就倒下了
If it was meningitis,we'd all be sick.
- 从脑脊液可以看出,- 毫无意义
His csf could show signs--that would be pointless.
已经做过脑组织活检, 是阴性
We already did a brain biopsy.It was negative.
有毒霉菌?
Toxic mold?
如果是霉菌, 我肯定病了
If it was toxic mold,I'd be sick.
我们怎么知道你没病?
How do we know you're not sick?
我样子很快活么?
Do I seem happy to you?
从没
Never.
有点好笑
It was funny.
暂时认定不从血液传播
Well,let's assume it's not blood-borne.
如果你开始讲笑话,我们再重新估计
If you start cracking jokes,we can re-assess.
同时, 远离你的亲友和宠物
In the meantime,stay away from people and animals that you care about.
Guillian-barr病?
Guillian-barr?
他们都没有出现麻痹症状
Neither of them had any sort of paralysis.
也许麻痹未来得及出现,Joe就已经死亡
Joe could have died before the paralysis had a chance to present.
会不会是虫媒病毒?
What about arbovirus?
开始治疗
Start treatment.
按虫媒病毒?
For arbovirus?
你觉得这个大都市的警察
You think our jersey beat cop
曾在蛮荒的非洲跟虫子在一起?
has been spending a lot of time exploring deep,dark africa?
任何治疗方向
Treatment for everything.
有谱的没谱的,只要能想到就治
Likely or unlikely.If you can think of it,treat for it.
这么多药物同时使用,会产生毒性
Mixing that many meds will create all sorts of toxic interactions.
那样会令肝肾不堪重负,肯定有更好的方法
We'll box his liver,trash his kidneys.There's got to be a better way.
当然有更好的方法!
Of course there's a better way!
都在Cuddy不让我们动的那具尸体上
It's that body sitting in the room with him that cuddy  won't let us touch.
细菌, 病毒, 毒素, 真菌, 寄生虫,必然是其中一种
Bacterials,virals,toxins,fungals,parasites.It's got to be one of them.
你去哪里?
Where are you going?
看能不能再找个大脑来检查
To see if I can find another brain to biopsy.
我们要把Joe锁在楼下,直到CDC到达
we're going to lock joe up downstairs until the cdc gets here.
Foreman, 你看不见
Foreman,you can't see.
对
Right.
House想给你一些药,在密封口里
House wants to start you on some meds.They're in the airlock.
治什么的?
For what?
最大的嫌疑是有毒的霉菌
Leading candidate is toxic mold.
cameron病了吗?
Is cameron sick?
我没事, 多谢关心
I'm fine.Thanks for asking.
你们这网撒的可有点大,不止是霉菌吧?
You're casting your net a little wider than toxic mold,aren't you?
Guillian-barr病也在台上放着
Guillian-barr?is also on the table.
还有椭圆形的...上面有个"L"或是"7"
This is an oval shape...has either an l or a 7.
我猜是个"L", 左氧氟沙星,因为不能排除细菌
I'm guessing an L.Levofloxacin,because you can't rule out bacteria.
8-0-0, 是阿昔洛韦的剂量,对付病毒
Eight,zero,zero.That's the dosage for the acylovir in case it's viral.
方的...不, 好像是菱形的
Square...no,more like a rhombus.
治真菌的氟康唑
That's fluconazole for fungus.
另外还有8种药, 你们
There's about eight others here.You--
你们把能想到的病都治了
you're treating me for everything.
你们不知道我得的什么
You have no idea what I've got.
House认为这是最好的措施
House thinks this is the best course of action.
House乱了方寸了
House is desperate.
他从来不乱
House is never desperate.
其中的一些药会起作用
Something we give you will work.
是啊, 以后所有的病人都这么治
Yeah,we should start treating all patients this way.
他们生病了, 就把所有的药吃了
When they get sick,they just take everything.
聊胜于无
It's better than doing nothing.
喂?
Hello?
我在警察家
I'm at the cop's place.
追溯你的脚步
I need to retrace your steps.
你觉得"百病皆治"还不保险?
You don't think the "treat him for everything" approach is enough?
你从哪里开始查的?
Where did you start your search?
厨房
The kitchen.
告诉我你做的每件事, 接触的每样东西
You will tell me everything you did,everything you touched.
即使上厕所,我也要知道时间和理由
If you went to the john,I want to know when and why.
从水槽的霉斑开始取样
I started with samples from the mold in his sink.
然后?
What next?
就那样, 然后离开了
That's it.Then I left.
现在干什么?
What do we do now?
等待steve mcqueen乐翻天
Wait for steve mcqueen to get giddy.
好计划
Excellent plan.
嘿, 爸爸
Hey,dad.
是Eric, 我不太好
It's eric.I'm not doing too good.
foreman怎么样了?
How's foreman?
你在玩网上摄像头?
You're accessing a webcam?
Cuddy的浴室偷拍
Cuddy's shower.
你喜欢巴西么? 我--
Are you a fan of the brazilian?I--
是你的厨房?
is that your kitchen?
当然, 我不能带到这儿来
Well,obviously I couldn't bring him here.
他已经接触到foreman碰过的东西
He's been exposed to whatever foreman's got.
你让steve受感染?
You infected steve?
干吗不从宠物店买一只?
Why didn't you just get a rat from the pet store?
因为...我需要病史清晰的老鼠
Because...I needed one with a clean medical history.
谁知道那些老鼠有没有用抗生素?
Who knows what kind of antibiotics they give those rats?
这就是你的计划?,坐这里看着你的老鼠?
So this is your plan?Just sit here and watch your rat all day?
应该很快的
Well,it shouldn't take long.
一切准备好, 我还清洗了笼子...
Got the ac blasting,I soaped the floor of his cage...
一旦发病, 就动手解剖
as soon as he gets sick,I do an autopsy.
一旦死亡
As soon as he's dead.
一旦发病, 它的头部会遭某个...
Right after he gets sick,there's a good chance he'll get hit in the head with A...
拐杖型器物的击打
cane-shaped object.
通常你只拿病人当小白鼠
Normally you just use your patients as lab rats.
这是个不错的改观
It's a nice change.
最先的症状是欣快
First symptom is euphoria.
你怎么知道老鼠是不是欣快?
How do you know if a rat's euphoric?
他平时不会这样爬水瓶的吧?
He doesn't usually climb on his water bottle like that,does he?
只有坐在车座上才出现症状
the seizures only seem to happen when she's in her car seat.
她颤动, 呻吟
She starts to rock and grunt.
对外界有反应么?
She responsive?
没有, 好像沉浸在她的世界
No,no,it's like she's in a zone.
还有她的腹肌张力异常
And her abdominal muscles become dystonic.
专业词
Big word.
某人上过互联网
Someone's been on the interweb.
我在"癫痫网"上看过几篇文章
I looked up a few articles on epilepsy.
有几个很不错的青年足球联盟
You know,there's actually some really great youth soccer leagues,
能照顾到她的特殊需求...
that would cater specifically to her special needs,and...
我想这就是为什么她不能适应学前班
I think it might explain why she's been having a hard time in preschool.
先让我确认你的诊断,然后再说退学的事
Let's confirm your diagnosis before you have her held back.
变幻的光线和高频的声音,会诱发癫痫
Strobing lights and high-pitched sounds can provoke a seizure.
你是傻瓜
You're a goof.
彼此彼此, 失败者
Takes one to know one,loser.
不是, 我说自己是失败者,这段剪掉
Wait,that means I'm a loser.Scratch that.
这些发作过程, 过后会不会出汗?
These episodes.She get sweaty afterwards?
湿透
Soaking wet.
她感到失落还是疲倦?
And does she seem upset by them,or just tired?
不, 她只是觉得好玩
No,she kind of thinks it's funny.
颤动, 呻吟, 出汗, 肌肉强直,再加上担心的父母
You mix rocking,grunting,sweating,and dystonia with concerned parents,
你在"癫痫网"上得到一个业余的诊断
and you get an amateur diagnosis of epilepsy.
实际上, 你女儿只是在"逗小妹妹玩"
In actuality,all your little girl is doing is saying "yoo hoo"to the "hoo hoo."
什么?
She's what?
企鹅行军
Marching the penguin.
姐妹情深
Ya-ya-ing the sisterhood.
"海底总动员",(电影, 讲少年成长的故事)
Finding nemo.
真好玩
That was funny.
这叫满足失调, 其实也不太准确
It's called gratification disorder.Sort of a misnomer.
不能满足自己, 那才叫失调
If one was unable to gratify oneself,that would be a disorder.
你是说她在自慰?
Are you saying she's masturbating?
说的隐晦点好吗, 有小朋友
I was trying to be discreet.There's a child in the room.
这太可怕了
Oh,this is horrifying.
"癫痫网"才叫可怕
Epilepsy is horrifying.
告诉你女儿注意隐私就没事了,给你
Teach your girl about privacy and she'll be fine.Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想在一个下午,把这个月的病人病历都弄妥?
One afternoon,and you're on pace to set the record for most patients seen in a month.
我坐堂门诊你不高兴?
You're upset that i'm doing clinic hours?
简直是婚礼上下雨的表情
Wow,that is so like rain on your wedding day.
刚才的3小时, 我一直在和CDC交涉,而你--
For the past three hours,I have been on the phone with the cdc,while you are--
交涉的怎样了?
yeah,how's that going, by the way?
他们答应加速处理--
They promised to expedite--
他们连尸体都没拿到, 做解剖未免难了点
tough to do an autopsy when they haven't even picked up the body.
你都不和病人在同一楼层,还奢谈什么治病
It's tough to treat your patient when you're not even on the same floor.
去吧, 门诊有人值班
Go.Clinic is covered.
看着药品滴注的过程
I go watch the meds drip into his iv.
你觉得这样有助于治疗吗?
You think that'll make the treatment work faster?
去办公室, 玩你的球
Go to your office.Play with your ball.
在白板上写字, 羞辱你的团队
Write on your whiteboard.Insult your team.
拿出你平常惯用的招数,只要解决问题
Do whatever it is that you do to figure things out.
感到内疚了?
Feeling guilty?
现在改变主意还不晚, 去打给CDC
It's not too late to change your mind.Go call the cdc.
告诉他们你开玩笑的
Tell 'em you were just joshing.
躲着Foreman直到他死掉
Keep avoiding foreman's case until he dies.
这样我就内疚了
Then I'll drown in guilt.
好些了么?
Feeling any better?
你怎么样?
How are you doing?
我不是病人
I'm not the patient.
你的血沉升高了?
Is your sed rate elevated?
没有
No.
看来我是走运的
So far,it looks like i lucked out.
Cameron.
你把止血带丢在床上了
Looks like you left a tourniquet on the bed.
你能看见了?
You can see again?
治疗起作用了
The treatment's working.
问题是, 哪种治疗?
The question is,which treatment?
每次减少一种药, 先去掉哪个?
We'll start weaning him off one at a time.Which one do we start with?
哪怕你按字母顺序也好,只要保持他的视力
I don't care if you do it alphabetically.Just stay on top of his vision.
一旦视力有消失的迹象,就说明去掉的药是有效的
First sign of regression means we've taken him off the wrong one.
最新的血检结果
The latest blood work.
Foreman的淀粉酶和脂肪酶,是正常值的三倍
Foreman's amylase and lipase levels are three times normal.
胰腺被破坏了
Pancreas is failing.
药物的副作用
A toxic side effect of his meds.
哲学问题
philosophical question.
你打算怎样死法?
How do you want to die?
老死
Old age.
你必须在从现在起4小时和14小时之间选
Your choice is currently between 4 hours from now and 14 hours from now.
估计你会选后者
So I'm assuming that means you want the latter.
鸡尾酒疗法有效
The cocktail's working.
视力几乎全部恢复
My vision's almost completely restored.
药物治疗了你的脑袋
The meds are curing what's in your head,
却摧毁了你的胰腺
but they're trashing your pancreas.
所以你会呕吐, 站直的力气都没有
That's why you're puking and you can't stand up without screaming.
降低剂量
So lower the dosages.
对胰腺损伤小点, 仍能对抗感染
Less stress on my pancreas, still battle the infection.
小剂量也有毒性
Lower dosages will still be toxic.
我不在乎!
I don't care!
我能忍受胰腺炎的疼痛
I can handle the pain of the pancreatitis.
但你不能忍受没胰腺的生活
I don't think you can handle life without a pancreas.
继续给你用药
We keep you on these meds,
你可以在生命的最后4小时,保留视觉
you'll spend the last four hours of your life being able to see.
取消用药, 你又变瞎子
Take you off,you'll go blind again.
但能争取时间,让我们弄清什么在侵蚀你的大脑
But it'll give us time to figure out what's eating your brain.
好吧
Fine.
我们怎么做
What do we do next?
eric?
爸爸?
Dad?
你们等会儿再叙旧
Yeah,you two can get caught up later.
先生, 请跟我来
Sir,I need you to come with me.
House.
这是什么?
Uh...what is this?
他不是什么, 是人
He isn't a what,he's a who.
还是个有投票权的
They even have the right to vote now.
Rodney foreman,cuddy. Cuddy,rodney foreman.
Rodney foreman - cuddy,Cuddy - rodney foreman
很高兴见到您, 女士
Nice to meet you,ma'am.
是Foreman的爸爸
This is foreman's dad.
我知道了
Yeah,I got that.
Cuddy医生是我们的主任
And dr. Cuddy,here,is the dean of medicine.
知道我跟你说的那个解剖吗
Remember that cool autopsy i was telling you about,
能救你儿子一命的?
the one that would save your son's life?
她有权批准解剖
She's the one can give us the green light to do it.
我能理解您为何不那样做
I understand you don't want them to do it.
House医生看来还没理解
Dr. House didn't seem to know why.
Foreman先生, 我一直尽力让CDC尽快--
Mr. Foreman,I am doing everything I can to get the cdc--
还是不够快
won't be soon enough.
关于我遵守公众健康安全守则的--
And my decision to follow public health safety protocols
别怪规矩不好
oh,don't blame the rules.
别把这都归罪于什么政策和守则
Don't want to hang this on policy and protocol.
我非常清楚, 您的儿子可能丧生,正如我清楚
I'm well aware that it may cost your son his life,just as I am well aware
我的决定能影响无数的家庭和朋友
that my decision has a devastating effect on family and friends
没在我眼前抗议的那些
without having them paraded in front of me.
你的儿子得了一种,未知的, 传染性的, 致命的感染
Your son has an unknown,contagious,deadly infection.
如果我们不能限制在这里,将有很多人处于危险
If we don't contain it here,even more people could be at risk.
我对那些人也负有责任
And I am capable of empathizing with those people too
即使他们没在我面前示威
without having them paraded in front of me.
我理解
I understand.
你的手怎么了?
What's wrong with your hand?
这叫肌肉痉挛
It's--it's called a muscle contraction.
我以为毛病在你头上
I thought this thing was in your brain.
是的, 这表明病源侵入了运动皮层
It is.It just means the infection's moved to the primary motor cortex,
那里控制肌肉
which controls the muscles.
是不是还很欣慰让我读医学?
Aren't you glad you sent me to med school?
疼吗?
Does it hurt?
不
No.
会疼吗?
Is it gonna?
另一个人
The--the other guy...
看上去不是很痛苦--
he didn't seem to suffer too much,he--
他睡着了
just went in his sleep.
Steve还是很正常?,没有痉挛的迹象
Steve still acting normal?,No sign of contractures.
他们把警察的尸体封在密封袋子里
They got the cop's body in a locked,airtight bag.
门口还有警卫
And a guard on the door.
这些联邦官员还真是紧张
These feds are seriously paranoid.
他几小时没尿尿了, 时间该到了
He hasn't gotten up to pee in hours.He's due.
你没朝他的多纳圈上洒泻药?
You haven't sprinkled senokot granules on his doughnut?
他的肠子会像红海分开一样翻腾
His bowels would open up like the red sea.
他不会吃多纳圈的
He wouldn't eat the doughnut.
你不是真的在这里待了几小时吧?
Have you seriously been dn here for hours?
没
No.
我去尿了几次
I had to pee a couple times.
不要再责怪cuddy了
You've got to stop blaming cuddy for this.
这是她的错, 责怪是应该的
Given that it is her fault,that seems appropriate.
她有错
That part is her fault.
某人在地下室浪费时间
The part where somebody wasted his time in the basement,
密谋放倒一个政府人员,那也是错
plotting the overthrow of a government agency,that one's on you.
我唯一可做的就是思考,在哪里无所谓
The only think I can do is think.I can pretty much do that anywhere.
只要没人烦我
As long as no one's bugging me.
给你兄弟打电话了吗?
did you call your brother?
没有
No.
你呢?
Did you?
没
No.
没什么大事
It's not a big deal.
我倒是想见妈妈
I sure would have liked to see mom,though.
你知道她无法旅行
You know she can't travel anymore.
你告诉她
You tell her?
做什么?
Why?
让她难过一阵
Just upset her for a while.
然后转眼就不记得了
Then she wouldn't remember for a while.
她不该知道吗?
Think she should know?
她已经记不起自己
She's lost a lot of who she was.
无法接受这样的事
She can't deal with something like this.
你能接受?
And you can?
我知道你会去一个美好的地方
I still know you're going to a better place.
你说的轻松
It's easy for you,isn't it?
只要你相信我会去好地方,死也没那么糟了
As long as you believe i'm going to a better place,dying ain't so bad.
我想让你不要怕
I don't want you to be afraid.
如果不怕死, 还能怕什么?
If I'm not afraid of dying,what the hell should I be afraid of,dad?
我以为你相信了
I thought you believed.
曾经
I did.
现在我不太确定了
I'm not so sure anymore.
我会为你祈祷, 儿子
I'm going to pray for you,son.
希望你和我一起
I suggest you do the same.
视野开始衰退
field of vision is regressing.
疼痛达到8级
And he's reached an eight on the pain scale.
病情发展和joe的一样
The disease pattern is following the exact course as joe'S.
在foreman身上更快
Only it's moving much faster in foreman.
好 这是不一致
Good!It's an anomaly.
不一致告诉我们很多,为何foreman更快, 有何区别?
Anomals tell us things.Why is this moving faster in foreman?What's different?
可能是同一种病的不同表型?
Could be a different strain of the same disease?
没错-我们寻找未知疾病是浪费时间
Right--we were wasting all this time looking for an unknown disease.
应该找同一疾病的不同表型
We should have been looking for a different strain of an unknown disease.
joe是警察
joe's a cop.
他要健身, 他也许...
He's into physical fitness,he could have had...
免疫系统更强, 代谢更强
a more powerful immune system,stronger metabolism.
Foreman是黑人
Foreman's black.
什么?
What?
你掌握这个信息多久了?
How long have you been sitting on this information?
狼疮, 痛风, 青光眼, 骨关节炎,高血压, 糖尿病
Lupus,gout,glaucoma,osteoarthritis,hypertension,diabetes,
说错了纠正我,这些病在黑人身上反应更大
stop me any time,they all affect black people more than whites.
每种都查
Check everything.
细菌, 真菌, 毒素, 寄生虫
Bacterials,fungals,toxins,parasites.
任何一种有种族差异的病
Look for anything with a documented racial disparity.
等等
Wait.
老鼠出现症状?
The rat's showing symptoms?
没
No.
他完全健康
He's completely healthy.
也许这就是Foreman和警察的区别
Maybe that's the difference between foreman and the cop.
感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
你来干什么?
Why are you here?
你是朋友, 我应该来
Because you're a friend. And I should be here.
对不起, House试图用我爸来操纵你
I'm sorry house used my dad to try and manipulate you.
你很坚定, 不会改变主意
You've got integrity,you aren't going to change your mind
面对我父亲也不会
just because you're confronted by my father.
谢谢
Thank you.
正如我不会原谅你
Just like I'm not going to forgive you
哪怕你来慰问我
just because you come by here and ask how I'm feeling.
你知道我别无选择
You know I've had no choice.
你有的选择!
Of course you had a choice!
规则写的很清楚
Regulations are clear.
不遵守规则受到的惩罚-
And the punishment for violating those regulations!
是死亡?
Is it death?
说实话, 我可以接受你被罚款, 被停职--
Because frankly,I'm okay if you get a fine,a suspension--
靠, 哪怕去坐几年牢,只要能救我的命!
hell,you can spend a couple of years in jail if it saves my life!
你死的太快
You're dying too fast.
完全同意
Couldn't agree more.
嗨, cuddy
Hey,cuddy.
探病愉快否?
Having a nice visit?
这是什么?
What's that?
军团--肺炎军团菌
Legionel--legionella pneumophila.
带着这么一瓶病菌干什么?
And why are you carrying a vial of it around with you?
Foreman感染之前完全健康
Foreman was perfectly healthy before he got this infection.
警察不是, 他有军团菌病
Our cop wasn'T.He had legionnaire's disease.
我们治好他的军团菌病之前,警察的大脑一直是好的
Our cop didn't turn into brain food until we cured the legionella.
军团菌延缓了疾病过程
Legionella slowed down the disease.
为什么会这样?
Why would that happen?
不知道 只知道确实如此
No idea.I just know that it did.
你想让foreman感染?
So you want to infect foreman?
你要和CDC打小报告?
Gonna tattle to the cdc?
药物不能治好我, 疾病可以?
Meds can't help me,but a disease can?
算了, 给我止疼,让我昏过去
Forget it!Just take the pain away and put me under.
让你昏过去, 就不能监测疼痛
If I put you under,I can't monitor your pain.
不监测疼痛就不知道军团菌是否有效
If I can't monitor your pain,I won't know if the legionella's working.
我不会授权你--
I'm not consenting to you giving me--
是什么?
what was that?
可惜没有一团魔烟升起
I wish there could have been a puff of smoke or something.
那样有戏剧性
Would've been much more dramatic.
穿着拖鞋
Keep your slippers on.
小心扎了脚
Wouldn't want you to cut your foot.
感觉好些了?
do you feel any better?
喘不过气, 头晕
I can't breathe.I'm dizzy.
我满耳朵都是肺部的杂音
And I can barely hear anything over the sounds of my lungs crackling.
就是军团菌病
That's the legionella.
你是从症状推断出?
You figure that out from the symptoms,
还是从地上的小瓶子?
or from the vial of stuff tossed in my room?
我只是想专业点,没必要冷嘲热讽
I'm trying to be professional here.There's no reason to be nasty.
- 我很痛苦,- house也是
I'm in pain.--So is house.
他开心的很
And he's a delight.
他不想杀死自己的同事
He doesn't try to kill his colleagues.
可以拿掉温度计了
You can remove the thermometer now.
降了整整一度
It's down almost a whole degree.
疼痛怎么样?
How's the pain?
好得很
Great.
好的那种
This is the good kind.
跟一小时前相比呢?
How bad is it compared to an hour ago?
没有恶化
No worse.
军团菌有用?
the legionella helping?
是
Yeah.
- 不错,- 还不够
Good.--Not great.
没有治好什么, 只是延缓
Didn't fix anything, it just slowed it down.
只需给steve多点时间发病
The point was to give steve a little more time to get sick.
如果他就是不病, 你怎么办?
What are you going to do if he never gets sick?
聪明
Brilliant.
Cameron,什么病感染人, 但不感染鼠?
Cameron,what type of illnesses affect humans,but not rats?
为什么问这个?
Why are you asking me that?
我确信你12岁之前肯定想做兽医
Because I'm sure that you spent the first 12 years of your life dreaming of ing a vet.
老鼠没有病, Cameron也没有
The rat is not getting sick.Cameron is not getting sick.
对不起
Sorry.
没关系, 不是你的错
It's okay,it's not your fault.
按照推断,你没病是因为不通过血液传播
Presumably,you're still healthy because whatever it is,is not bloodborne.
Steve就说不过去,他做了所有foreman做过的
Steve has no excuse.He did everything that foreman did.
有些细菌不感染鼠类
Some bacterial infections don't infect rats.
Foreman测过每一种感染大脑的细菌,全是阴性
Foreman tested negative for every bacterial infection that would affect his brain.
哪种病菌他可能有, 但又查不出?
And what infections could he be positive for,but test negative for?
我们检测的其实是抗体
When we test for infections,we look for antibodies.
万一病人受了感染, 却没产生抗体?
But what if the patient is infected,but has no antibodies?
如果身体不对抗感染?
What if the body is not fighting the infection?
为什么会--
Why would--
我先问的
I asked first.
先解答是什么. 然后说为什么
Let's start with the what.We'll deal with the why later.
如果身体不能识别感染,检测就是阴性
If the body doesn't recognize the infection,our tests come back negative,
于是疾病不受阻挡地肆虐
and the disease rampages through the body unstopped.
正如警察和Foreman那样
Exactly like the cop and exactly like foreman.
如果病人又接受第二种感染?
And what if the patient was then exposed to a second infection?
比如军团菌?
Like legionella?
身体会认出它, 增加白细胞数量
The body would recognize that infection,increase the white count,
派出部队, 抵御入侵
send in the troops to start fighting,
结果最初的感染遇到了打击
and the initial infection would get caught in the crossfire.
问题变成
So the question becomes,
什么东西感染人但不感染老鼠?
what type of bacterial infection  affects humans but not rats,
而且不易被身体识别?
and the human body would be unlikely to recognize?
答案是李氏杆菌
The answer is listeria.
准备上氨苄加庆大
I'm starting you on ampengent.
你的理论依据是, 测试阴性而且-
So you're basing this theory on the test being negative
你的老鼠健康?
and your rat being healthy?
还有军团菌对你有效
And the fact that legionnaire's is helping you.
但你给我的药会中止这一切
But the medicine you want to give me will put an end to that.
是
Yeah.
如果不是李氏杆菌,却治好军团病
And if it's not listeria,all the gent will do is cure the legionnaire's disease
另一种病起死回生,会要我的命
and put whatever is killing me back into overdrive.
问问题之前不要假定我错
Stop asking me questions based on the premise that I'm wrong.
抗生素在密封口里
The antibiotics are in the airlock.
第一次活检没有结果
I think the first biopsy didn't give us the answer
因为你挖的不够深
because you didn't go deep enough.
我要做脑白质检查
I want you to do a white matter brain biopsy.
是啊, 也不能怪你
Absolutely.Don't blame you.
对于一个有高级推理能力的人,世界太复杂了
The world is such a complicated place if you've got higher reasoning skills.
我也羡慕小动物和弱智儿童
I'm often jealous of small animals and retarded children.
用抗生素
Take the antibiotics.
如果做得对, 损伤可以很小
There can be minimal damage if it's done right.
如果手术组在我告诉他们的地方钻孔
If the surgeons drill where I tell them to drill.
稍有偏差 你下半辈子,会成为一个流着口水的白痴
One slip--you could spend the rest of your life not being able to keep your drool in your mouth.
我宁可残废也不想死
I'd rather be disabled than dead.
当然,  我瘸的很性感
Sure,I make it look oh so sexy.
实际上没你想的那么风光
It's actually not as glamorous as you might think.
活检会告诉我们哪里出问题
The biopsy will tell us for sure what's wrong.
抗生素也可能
The antibiotics could do the same thing.
可能, 不是能
Could,not will.
我们试试再说
We try it,we see.
抗生素会带给我疼痛
The antibiotics will bring back the pain.
疼痛促使我们做出坏决定
Pain makes us make bad decisions.
惧怕疼痛...可以成为一个动机
Fear of pain...is almost as big a motivator.
我么还有时间
Look,we still have time.
如果需要做活检 我会的
I will do that biopsy if I have to.
不到万不得已
But not a moment before.
给foreman静注抗生素,他爸在哪里?
Start foreman on I.V. Antibiotics.Where's his dad?
你儿子要死的时候你会在哪?
Where are you supposed to be when your son is dying?
他没陪在身边
He's not with him.
他在教堂
He's in the chapel.
我为你儿子设定了一个新疗法
I started your son on a new course of treatment.
如果有效, 他会好起来
If it works,he'll get better.
如果无效, 不会好
If it doesn't,he won'T.
非但不会好
While he's not getting better,
还要经历巨大的疼痛
he's going to experience so much pain
我们只能用化学方法诱导昏迷
that we'll have to put him in a chemically-induced coma
直到我们想出办法
while we figure out what to do next.
我儿子说你是个控制欲的混蛋
My son says you're a manipulative bastard.
那是我的小名
It's a pet name.
我叫他dr. Bling.
I call him dr. Bling.
我想你来是有原因的,你想要什么?
I assume you're here for a reason.What do you want from me?
当你儿子陷入昏迷
When your son is in a coma,
只能由你为他做出医学上的决定
you're the one who's going to have to make the medical decisions for him.
随便, 你说了算
Oh,whatever you decide is fine.
你不管我做什么?
You don't care what I do?
我不是医生, 我能知道什么?
I'm not a doctor.What do I know?
我只知道eric说过
Except what eric tells me.
他说你是他共事过的最好的医生
He says you're the best doctor he's ever worked with.
帮我一个忙
I need your help.
对你的疼痛我无能为力
There's nothing I can give you for the pain.
我想昏过去
I want to be put out.
5分钟后会有护士来
I can have a nurse in here in five minutes.
不, 帮我一个忙
No.Want some help.
我也许醒不过来
I might not come back.
我没立遗嘱
I've never done a will.
我给你找律师
I'll call a lawyer for you.
我要你做我的患者代理人
I want you to be my medical proxy.
令我对你不忿的那些方面--
All the things that piss me off about you in house's office--
你的感情化, 过于关爱, 过于谨慎--
you're too emotional,too caring,too cautious--
在这里都是好事
they're all good things on this floor.
- 你爸爸在--,- 不
- Your dad is,-no.
- 他关心你,- 你也是
- He cares about you.-,-So do you.
我不能
I can't do this.
我们期待家属为他们的家人做出决定
We expect family members to make decisions about their loved ones
仅凭10分钟的介绍
after a ten-minute briefing
却忽视我们从医数年的经验
that we're agonizing over even with years of medical experience.
这是我文章里的
That's from my article.
对不起, allison
I'm sorry,allison.
我不该偷你的论文,不该让你感染
I shouldn't have stolen your article.I shouldn't have exposed you.
你是朋友
You were a friend.
我想知道我们没事了
I need to know that we're okay.
不
No.
我会做你的代理人,但我们还没完
I'll be your proxy,but we're not okay.
你怕你要死了,所以你想把一切做对
You're scared you're dying.And that's the only reason you want to set things right.
我们会先治好你
We're going to get you better first,
然后, 如果你想道歉, 我就在这里
and then, if you still want to apologize,I'll be around.
我去叫律师
I'll call that lawyer.
有进展么?
Any improvement?
目前来看
Well,as far as we can tell,
抗生素只是治疗了军团菌
the only thing the antibiotics are treating is the legionella.
我们要另想主意了
I think we need to consider alternate theories.
例如?
Like what?
我们做个活检--
We do the biopsy.We--
再试一段抗生素
give the antibiotics more time.
没时间了,疼痛几乎无法忍受
There is no more time.The pain is almost unbearable already.
几乎无法忍受, 又不是几乎要死
So he's almost in unbearable pain.He's not almost dead.
这说明我们还有时间
Which means we have more time.
Foreman先生?
Mr. Foreman?
我们要让你儿子昏迷
We need to put your son in a coma.
你要在场
You should be there.
这是医院的程序?
It's a medical procedure,right?
是
Yeah.
如果我们让他昏迷, 又不能解决
But once we put him out,if--if we don't solve this,
他不会醒来
he won't wake up.
我该说什么?
What should I say?
跟他说些宽心的话?
Should I talk to him like it's going to be...okay?
还是跟他道别?
Or should I be saying good-bye?
我想知道大家都是怎么说--
I need to know what people say when--
只需说你爱他
just tell him you love him.
嗨, 儿子
Hey,son.
嗨, 爸爸
Hey,dad.
会好起来的
It's going to be okay.
你不知道
You don't know that.
我知道
I know.
你不知道
You don'T.
我不想失去你
I don't want to miss you.
我也爱你, 爸爸
I love you too,dad.
嗨
Hey.
会好的
It's gotta to be okay.
- 可以开始了么?,- 当然
Can we do this now?--Yeah,of course.
我接受你的道歉
I accept your apology.
你怎么不在foreman身边?
Why weren't you with foreman?
我在地下室徘徊, 你嘲笑我
I hang out in the basement,you rag on me.
我呆在办公室, 你嘲笑我
I stay in my office,you rag on me.
你就是不能消停
Honkey just can't buy a break.
做活检
Do the biopsy.
根据警察的病情发展,我认为他还有4个小时--
Based on the cop's progression,I figure he's got about another four hours--
你认为?
you figure?
你是在玩俄罗斯轮盘赌,枪却顶在他头上
You're playing russian roulette,but the gun's pointed at him.
不, 切开他的脑袋才是危险的
No,cutting open his head is what's dangerous.
哦, 危险,人们会怎么想?
Oh,it's dangerous.Well,what would people think?
你不看病人是因为, 一旦你认识他们
The reason you don't see patients is because if you know them,
- 你就恶言恶语,- 我认识你
you'll give a crap about them. --I know you.
如果你恶言恶语, 就不会胡来
If you give a crap, you stop making outrageous calls.
如果是别的病人
If this was any other patient,
你才不在乎什么风险,早就切开他们的脑袋
you'd have damned the risk and cut their head open a long time ago.
他昏迷了, 但是脑电波显示还在疼痛
He's out. The eeg shows he's still in pain.
抗生素试够了, 我们做大脑活检
The antibiotics have had more than enough time.We're doing the brain biopsy.
除非在接下来的3小时内,我们想不出更好的主意
Not unless you people can't come up with something clever in the next three hours.
现在就做
Now.We're doing it now.
- 谁让你当上老板了?,- Foreman
Who died and made you boss?--Foreman.
合法的
It's legal.
他神志不清
he's out of his mind.
昨天他还嘲笑别人头上的洞
Yesterday he was giggling about a hole in a guy's head.
让律师来寻找破绽,与此同时, Cameron说了算
Then hire a lawyer and challenge it.In the meantime,cameron's in charge.
他为什么要签这个?
Why would he sign that?
并不针对谁, Foreman先生
It's nothing personal,mr. Foreman.
我儿子不信任我, 怎么会不针对谁?
My son doesn't trust me.How exactly is that not personal?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你遗憾?
You're sorry?
你说的是他的儿子
You're talking about this man's son.
- 你否决他的参与,- 闭嘴吧, house.
You're denying him the right to be a part of--oh,shut up,house.
你想做活检就做
If you want to do the biopsy,do the biopsy.
如果house要阻挠就告诉我,我来摆平他
If house tries to interfere,let me know and I will take care of it.
是啊, 你真威风
Yeah.You're a hero.
如果不是你, 我们现在应该,在切死尸的头, 而不是foreman
If it wasn't for you,we'd be cutting into a dead guy's head instead of foreman'S.
对不起
Sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 够生猛!,- 粗鲁而且无必要
That was great!--It was rude and unnecessary.
是啊
Yeah.
走开
Go away.
给我点时间
Give me time.
- 没时间了,- 1小时
We're out of time.--An hour.
懂不懂什么叫没时间?
What does "out of time" mean?
他的氧饱和度是94
His o2 stats are 94 right now.
肺是90, 发生致命心律失常,的危险不会增加
His lungs are about 90.The danger of fatal arrhythmia doesn't increase.
那又如何? 等待全无意义
So what?There's no point in waiting.
你是对的, 我们应该切尸体的头
You were right.We should be cutting into a corpse's head.
是应该, 可尸体在CDC手里
Yeah,we should be,except the cdc's got the cop's body--
应该有其它尸体
there's got to be other bodies.
你觉得这病还杀死其他人?
You think this thing has killed other people?
不
No.
他的公寓是个垃圾堆
That apartment was a dump.
steve mcqueen没得病,不代表其它小动物没得
Just because steve mcqueen didn't get sick doesn't mean some other vermin didn'T.
给我一小时, 我回去找个死去的动物
You give me an hour.I go back there,I find a dead animal,
我切开"它"的头,保住Foreman的
I cut its head open instead of foreman'S.
Foreman在吸纯氧
Foreman's already on 100% oxygen.
氧饱和过90, 我就不能再等
Once his o2 seds hit 90,I can't wait any longer.
你的防护服呢?
Where's your suit?
你我总有一人能找出答案
Either you'll find the answer,or I'll find the answer.
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
安置钻头
put the drill.
随时做好手术准备
we gotta be ready to go if we get the signal.
92.
我找到一只瞎鸟
I found a blind bird.
太好了
Great.
多快能抓到?
How fast can you get it in here?
大约30秒后
I'll know in about 30 seconds.
你最好抓到 它, 手术组已经到位
You better have the bird.The surgical team's in place.
我的错
I screwed up.
你抓不到一只瞎鸟?
How can you not capture a blind bird?
不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
我上次来的时候犯错了
I screwed up the first time through this place.
Foreman把去过的地点告诉你
Foreman told you everywhere he went.
不在地点, 在于时间
It's not where,it's when.
他是午后来的
He came here early afternoon.
我和steve来晚了两小时,你来早了6小时
Me and steve came through two hours too late.You were six hours early.
是水, 灌溉系统泵入--
It's the water.The irrigation system only pumps--
house, 我查过水, 水没问题
house,I tested the water.The water's clean.
House.
没找对水
We tested the wrong water.
他偷有线电视, 偷肥料, 还偷水
He stole cable,he stole fertilizer,and he stole water.
漂满了阿米巴虫
It's riddled with naegleria.
我知道
I know.
你已经做了活检
You already did the biopsy.
我以为没得选择
I thought I had no choice.
我儿子怎么样?
How's my son?
原发性阿米巴脑膜脑炎
He has primary amebic meningoencephalitis.
一种寄生虫,通过鼻腔迁移到大脑
It's a parasite that goes through the nose and migrates into the brain,
以脑细胞为食
where it feeds on brain cells.
军团菌攻击这种寄生虫,所以延缓了疾病
The legionella attacked the parasite.That's why the disease slowed down.
能治吗?
Is it treatable?
给他用了抗原虫药
We started him on an antiparasitic,
能清除阿米巴虫
and the amoebas will clear out of his system.
然后就没事了?
And he'll be okay?
然后--停止昏迷措施
Then--then we'll wean him out of the coma--
他会好么?
will he be okay?
寄生虫不会造成永久性损伤
There'll be no lasting damage from the parasite.
但手术会?
But the surgery?
还不知道
We don't know.
感觉怎样?
How are you feeling?
能说话么?
Can you talk?
感觉不到
I don't feel anything.
你没感觉?
Are you numb?
我...我是说
No,I--I mean...
感觉不到疼了
I don't feel any pain.
头不要动, 跟着我的手指
Keep your head still.Follow my finger.
我很好
I'm okay.
你口臭, 而且尿在一个袋子里
Your breath stinks.And you're peeing into a bag.
我们的名字?
What are our names?
你做了活检?
You did the biopsy?
谢谢
Thank you.
名字?
Names?
Cameron.
我爸
My dad.
还有爱控制人的混蛋
And the manipulative bastard.
记起来了
You remembered.
你怎么样, 爸爸?
How you doing,dad?
很好
Great.
放松了, 很好
Relieved.Great.
我得的什么病?
What did I have?
阿米巴虫
Naegleria.
活检发现虫,CDC的解剖也发现了
Biopsy showed the amoeba.Cdc autopsy eventually found the amoeba.
house在警察家的房顶的水里找到了
And house found it in the water on the cop's roof.
动一下左边脚趾
Wiggle your left toes.
等等
wait,wait.
你回去了, 她做的活检?
You went back and she did the biopsy?
你的左脚趾, Foreman
Your left toes,foreman.
动了
I just did.
不, 你没动
No,you didn'T.
他的脚趾不能动了?
He can't move his toes?
他能动
He can move them.
抬起你的右手
Raise your right arm.
怎么了?
What?